Ryan P. Roderick Web Developer

Ryan@DesignMonster.com

www.DesignMonster.com

About Me

I am a web developer with a history in metal fabrication, forging, and engineering. In 2016 I pursued my goal to work in the field of Technology. Web Development allows me to bring the skills I've learned throughout my fabrication career into a new and exciting territory. My passion for building things and my desire to create has always fueled my choices, and it's this same passion that led me to Development. I have spent the last three years teaching myself how to be a web developer, building side projects, completing an internship, and contributing to open source.

Coding Skills

- JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS
- Ember including Octane, React, Vue
- Rails, Node, SQL, MONGO

Work Experience

Web Developer Design Monster, LLC Camden, ME

02/2017 - Present

- Work with small businesses and entrepreneurs to make their vision a reality
- Specializes in Ember.js
- Turn ideas into functional products that do exactly what they were designed to do
- Development and consultation work to facilitate emergent technologies and create innovative products

Web Developer Internship

TenLegs

Remotely

06/2017 - 11/2017

- Worked remotely in a collaborative environment with other developers, front and back end, and UX/UI leaders to complete sprints on time and with best coding practices
- Learned best practices in a team environment utilizing such tools as JIRA, KANBAN, GIT (with GitLab), and attended morning meetings (remotely) using AGILE structure
- Strengthened CSS3, SASS, SCSS, HTML, HBS and JS skills through various tasks
- Focused on Ember.js and front-end responsiveness. Tasks included refactoring components to fit specific client needs, building all new functionality when needed, and restructuring the entire application from a block system to Flexbox

Web Developer In-Training

General Assembly

Boston, MA

- · Designed, planned, documented, and executed four projects from start to finish
- Developed User Stories and implemented UI and UX solutions
- Reviewed different methodologies of programming, such as Object Oriented Design and Agile Development
- Covered basic IT and CS concepts, along with general software concepts like security, database relationships, and layering.
- · Worked in Bash shell, utilized node.js, npm and bower packages, and learned best practices of Git and GitHub

Shipfitter Metal Fabrication

Portsmouth Naval Shipyard

Kittery, ME

02/2014 - 09/2016

- Active member of teams responsible for the on-time redeployment of Nuclear Powered Submarines; duties included engineering, fabrication, and deployment of structural components with teams across every trade
- Successfully completed various duties, tasks, and projects on board U.S. Nuclear Submarines, including but not limited to: fabrication, weld preparation, use of all manner of machinery and design
- Working at the Portsmouth Naval Shipyard introduced me to working on large projects while interacting with numerous smaller groups, each tasked with completing their own parts of a much larger picture. The day to day details of my work varied greatly, ranging from completing small tasks or even just parts of small tasks, to putting the finishing touches on whole projects and signing off on their completion 06/2017-

Education

Data Visualization Certificate (in progress)	FreeCodeCamp	Remotely
11/2020 - present		
Front End Libraries Certification	FreeCodeCamp	Remotely
07/2020 - 10/2020		
JS Algorithms and Data Structure Certification	FreeCodeCamp	Remotely
04/2020 - 07/2020		
Responsive Web Design Certification	FreeCodeCamp	Remotely
01/2020 - 04/2020		
Web Developer Internship	TenLegs (now Bluespace)	Remotely
06/2017 - 11/2017		
Web Development Immersive	General Assembly	Boston, MA
10/2016 - 01/2017		